Hello everyone and thank you so much for joining
us for our first Digital Connect event of spring
2021 semester. Today we will be focused on virtual
career fair success my name is Alyssa Rametta and
I serve as an assistant director at Career and
Professional Development here at Virginia Tech
and I'll be your moderator for today. So before I
have the panelists introduce themselves I'm going
to give a brief overview of what to expect
in the next hour and a half in our structure
so we'll begin our conversation today with our
most commonly asked pre-submitted questions
that some of our audience members submitted during
registration and then we will open the panel up to
live questions so you can submit um your questions
on the right side there's a discussion tab you
can type in your questions at any point and we
will get to as many well in the first 45 minutes
then at 4 15 we will end the panel discussion
and this broadcast you'll go back to the main
lobby and enter the chat booths that you can
talk to any of our representatives today here
um and also move into the networking booths
with career and professional development
advisors to ask more questions and you'll be able
to experience what it's like to attend a career
fair in prison i will let our panelists
give a brief introduction to themselves
and their companies we are waiting for one
um representative from mantec to join us
she's having some technical difficulties such
a thing in 2020 and 2021 but in the meantime
let's have our panelists introduce
themselves i'm going to start with geico
and then the southern teachers association and
then hopefully mantec geico you can take it away
well hello everybody my name is allison hanson i
am the corporate and technical campus recruiter
uh here at geico there's only one of us and
it's me um so i'm really excited to get to
give you guys uh my unique experiences as a
recruiter and some of the things that i've seen
hi i'm maggie i work with southern teachers
and we specialize in teacher recruitment
for independent schools in the south so we work
with schools that are kindergarten pre-k through
12 and we do teacher placement as well as some
administrative placement and school consulting
but obviously what's important to you all is the
teacher placement aspect of it um and so really
we talk about things from the job search point
of view and how we help candidates connect with
the 650 schools that we do work with um and how
we can help in your job search that way great
thank you both so much so i'm gonna go right into
our pre-submitted questions because we have a lot
of them um at any point for our audience members
please um enter some questions into the discussion
board and we'll get to as many as possible so
the first question for both of you what would
you say are the major differences that you see
between an in-person and virtual career fairs
um so one of the things i would say a big
difference is is the ability to just jump in jump
out people think i can just log on and log off
what that can mean the danger of that is someone
logs on for five minutes without necessarily
being professionally prepared that's something
we've seen a couple times in the fall you know
you're in your dorm room that's absolutely fine
take a couple minutes look at what's behind you
you know if your roommate is playing music maybe
ask them to turn it down have showered for the
morning just general things that you would look
after if you were going to a job fair event just
make sure that that's first on your checklist to
take care of because we have seen some people miss
those queues because it's been a stressful year
100 i really couldn't agree with more like
i definitely have had people who popped in
and i'm like oh are you are you wearing
a shirt you know you kind of you're like
no you're listening you laughed but it's it's been
a thing and so it's just one of those uh one of
those aspects of it that we don't think of but
even more more than not being just prepared for
the day not being prepared to know what you're
gonna say um be ready to talk about yourself
you know having your two-minute uh personal
statement ready to go is super important um
maybe even having a question or two
prepared it's gonna make you seem more
interested in the company itself um and
that will stand out to your recruiter
great thanks and feel free to chime in after each
other as well you don't have to just answer one
time so if you can feed off of each other um and
i may add my two cents into as a career advisor
uh so thinking posts um how should sorry pre-fair
how should students be preparing for the career
fair and what materials might they need that
would differ from an in-person career fair
so one of the things you can do and that that
kind of crosses over is linking to any social
media like a linkedin or something like that um
which can be great if you have a linkedin set up
and it's easier to do digitally and so you have
your resume and then you have these additional
digital materials again just make sure that those
materials are as reviewed and refined as your
resume itself um that's that's something we've
seen people do that can be a great addendum to
your personality when you're constrained in the
way you present it um but then also i would just
going back to that earlier question um one of the
things that is limited by a digital career fair
as an input instead of an in-person one is your
ability to browse when you're in an in-person fair
you can just pop in and pop out and that's okay
from different stalls and you run into someone or
they pull you into the question so you know go in
with some research places you want to talk to and
then don't be afraid to browse around and look at
the others and you can say i came here with some
questions for some other people just saw yours
and would like to talk to you that also works
you're right i'll agree i see more people
who often come to my booth they're like
oh i wanted to talk to geico and it's like
well that's great and i'm i'm excited that
you're here but have you looked at other
places you know from just a recruiter
to oh my goodness guys recruiter
perspective making sure that you're
actually getting out there and getting
your resume seen is very important
great thanks so i think you both started
on this a little bit but what would you
say are the most important qualities that
you're looking for in a potential hire
i'll happen first uh minor
means that we we're going to have very different
answers to this so i'm really interested to hear
what ali has to say as well um you know singing
to what geico looks for we're looking for
data driven individuals um so usually you
know you have regardless of what field
you're in you're going to have some um analytical
exposure right um you're gonna be somebody who's
always looking for the next step ambitious
most people within the company have promoted
uh one-third of all associates every year promote
from their current position into a new position
so we want to be sure that the people who are
coming in are ambitious and are looking for the
next step in their career you know we're looking
for people who are looking for those careers you
know not just the not just the job um loyalty has
been something that uh has built geico from what
it was in 1936 to what it is today and something
that we're going to keep doing um so data driven
ambitious um and passionate passionate work
guys thanks alison yeah so we we definitely
are coming from different angles in different
communities which i think is great um so
just as a bit of background on how southern
teachers works because we work with independent
schools who don't necessarily have to hire
secondary teachers with certifications
a lot of the schools we work with will look for
candidates with a strong academic background
in their field so fluency in their language
you know a strong stem background and some
experience with kids you don't necessarily
have to have gone through an education program
although it's wonderful if you have um so that
being said what they're looking for is that strong
academic background and then some experience with
kids if you've been a camp counselor that's a
great experience if you've done some tutoring
awesome and then independent schools they're
looking for someone who's going to be a part of
their community i'm sure everyone remembers that
their high school their teachers were also their
coach where they were in this after school program
they were invested in that community
to create a good experience for the
for the students in so many different ways
and so someone who really is willing to
be a part of the school community and help
the kids grow in more than just standing
in front of in front of the class every day
but that is of course the key component so
that it's just that strong academic background
and the willingness to invest in the community
great i'm going to step away from some of
the pre-submitted questions for a moment to
answer a question submitted in the discussion
board so how do you avoid the barrier of zoom
fatigue that we all know very well right now
um while you're doing these interviews and
uh ritual career fairs so how
to battle that zoom fatigue
very very excited um i have the opportunity to
speak to several students um a week i mean doing
that back to back zoom calls are often uh my often
my days right so one thing that i have done is
i've actually started taking a couple of meetings
standing up um and i know that that sounds really
um that sounds really interesting uh but making
sure that you have your area set up just as ali
suggested making sure that you whatever is around
you is professional and appropriate you know
standing up while you're doing interviews is
not it's not going to be frowned upon so long
as you're doing it in a professional manner so
that's one way that i know that i do on a daily
basis to try to counteract some of that fatigue
honestly for me the answer is very simple it's um
just hang upside down like do some
stretches then if you can do a headstand
do a headstand against the wall or just bend at
the waist just take a second and like bend over
be in your body act like you're a human in the
world instead of just facing the screen and it
makes all the difference just to breathe for a
second and not not be looking at something not
putting your attention to anything else just to
stop for a moment that always helps helps for me
and i'm going to take a moment
to introduce tiffany here hi
so glad that your internet and breathing could
finally go through welcome welcome um why don't
you just take a moment tiffany to introduce
company that you're representing um and maybe your
your number one um thing that you're looking
for in a potential hire at a virtual career fair
that's one thing that we've covered so far sorry
it's the number one thing i'm looking to hire
yeah what you're looking for in a potential hire
gotcha gotcha okay so first hi everyone so sorry
for the delay um it's so ironic this discussion
is about how to prepare for a virtual career fair
and of course my uh my laptop was
not prepared so don't do what i did
um so i'm actually calling in through
mobile phones so yay iphones um
to help navigate through work laptop issues um
so i'm tiffany ann i am the college recruiting
manager and diversity outreach lead
for nantech international core um so i
i run the whole program of interns and new grads
and and work with diversity partners and create
pipelines for man tech and it's super fun
it's super invigorating and it's amazing
because i get to meet awesome students just like
yourselves uh when i'm at a virtual career fair
one quality that i always look for in a in a
candidate in a top candidate is ambition drive
and innovation uh we're in a changing world all
the time as you see in 2020 was like the epitome
of what a changing world looks like so someone who
can adapt and be resourceful and innovate and and
help us all you know keep up with the adjustments
help us all survive you know in innovation
whether it's systems and stem um in any part of
business so that's that's what i'm looking for
great thank you so much and i'm so
glad that you were able to join us
um so the next question is what about the students
who have never been to a career fair before in
person or virtual what advice do you have for them
um for their first career fair being on brazen
i would say i think that you you all you know
giving them brazen as their platform you know
first and foremost puts them as a at an advantage
almost for their uh for their first virtual
fare being uh on brazen right you guys
are gonna be able to have that one-on-one
interaction with your recruiter you can
make it last the impression that you have
in that one-on-one setting is more impactful um is
extremely impactful uh especially compared to what
it was like in a one-on-one setting even at you
know a large-scale recruiting event on campus um i
don't have a million other students you know with
their resumes in my face it is me and you so use
that opportunity to make the impact that you want
to make um you guys are really at an advantage
that's great thanks anybody else chime in
sure uh so i i second that so it is a very
interesting thing virtual career fairs
so if you can imagine if you guys have been to you
know in person career fairs just imagine you're
walking through crowds and you're fighting
through you know your classmates trying to
get to the recruiter or the or the engineer that
they're at the stand and trying to fight for time
so it's very true what allison mentioned is
that this is such an advantage this is your time
so don't be afraid if you've never been to a
career fair let alone a virtual career fair
now is the perfect time to start now's the perfect
time to jump feet in because you do have that
dedicated whether it's five minutes 10 minutes
15 minutes whatever the system allows you to have
you have the dedicated face-to-face one-on-one
time with that recruiter or that company
representative so the best thing for you is to
be prepared right you already know you're gonna
get one-on-one video time with somebody from that
company now it's time to make a good impression
come prepared with questions and i can tell off
the top of my head right now i can tell you the
top five i think it's five most asked questions
uh from students in these virtual chat rooms or
virtual career fairs is what does your company
do uh what does the internship program look like
uh where do i apply how is covid been treating
the employees and has your company been
uh you know helping its employees through the
pandemic um and how long will it take for me
to hear back so those were the most common
questions you can use those but i'm gonna
say you know what take it one step further
ask more about the position do some research
of the company prior to speaking right if you're
asking what does your company do you know if
you can you can look it up let's let's make a
good impression come prepared with meaningful
lasting questions that really get a real
conversation going between you and that
person because you do have that 10 minutes
all to yourself and you know that's how you
make that connection in that virtual setting
and just to build off that because of the
duration and you're right that one-on-one focus
it almost is more like a mini job interview than
a brief connection at a job fair where you
get someone's card you get a freebie piece of
swag and then you move on um and so we always tell
students and candidates that the best interviews
you come away feeling like you had a conversation
with the interviewer you felt like there was an
interaction and an exchange so questions are
a good way to do that and also just rolling
with the technical difficulties something's
gonna happen you're gonna talk over each other
in a normal first job search these things
can be anxiety inducing inducing anyway
over tech it can be a little bit worse
because your cues are just a little off
just take a deep breath slow down say i'm
sorry what did you say you can just slow down
and resort to good manners that's always the
simplest thing to do in a job fair when you're
meeting a lot of new people worst comes to worst
take a step back and be polite and that's going
to help you build a stronger interpersonal
interaction with that person and leave a good
impression even if you're thrown off your game a
little bit due to the nature of the interaction
that's a really great point and actually
i'm going to jump over to another question
having to do because you mentioned interpersonal
communication over video chat does anybody
have tips on how to build an authentic
connection with an employer over video chat
so i'll start don't be afraid to feel vulnerable
you know it's it's sometimes it's scary whether
it's in a face-to-face interview or video chat
you know don't be afraid to feel vulnerable like
and and you people will make mistakes and
you might say the wrong thing or do the
wrong thing but it's okay i mean take me for
instance my laptop wasn't working i was late
i thought it was you know i checked it before
to make sure i could connect and in the end
it didn't and you know i i messed up and i didn't
prepare well enough and that's okay you know we're
in a virtual setting we all make mistakes so
just know that if you want to build an authentic
relationship with the person you're talking to
be your authentic self smile you know be happy to
talk about you and your passion your hobbies why
you are in this field whatever you're interviewing
for why are you interested in the first place
do your research oh this company um has produced
you know this widgets and and you know that's so
cool because if this this you know goes into my
passion so be your authentic self when you show
up smile be interested ask meaningful questions
great anybody else authentic
connection over video chat
i think it's been built for me
pretty naturally by just saying
this is sort of the space i'm calling from like
if there's something you know at the beginning
of our talk you mentioned your house plan and
it's just exactly that sort of thing where we
have these different spaces we're not relating to
each other from the space same space so you can
say even if it's something is like oh i'm just
adjusting my light or let me move my cam like
acknowledging the moment you're in the space from
which you're interacting gives the person a sense
of where you're at the setting you're in you
know if your if your roommates are going to be
making noise you can say i'm sorry the most
safest place i could call from was my dorm room
you may hear some noises or there's construction
outside just acknowledge the setting for what it
is if something happens explain what it is roll
with it and move on and that's going to show
your employ potential employer how you handle
difficulties problems what have you just take
accountability for it and say this is
what it is and this is where i am yeah
right like that's what you know they've shown
that you can be adaptable to those situations um
for myself you know it all kind of ties together
just showing you know the candidate or not even
showing the candidates excuse me i'm showing the
recruiter that you're human and it it boils down
to also us showing you guys that you know we're
human like ali and tiffany but or i'm sorry ally
to me and alyssa kind of you know alluded to
right like this is my gecko this is gary like i
i purposely have included my i'm in my bedroom
and gary the gecko is hanging out on my dresser
so like you know i i bring people in and it's like
this is you know where we are this is what we're
doing and we've been on video calls for a while
so as you guys are entering into these video chats
understand that the people you are with
are likely less nervous than you are so
take that deep breath you know just like answering
questions you want to think about your responses
don't be afraid to take a deep breath and assess
the situation right assess where they're at i'm
going to assess what you're doing and what your
camera is just take a deep breath and internalize
where you're at i mean hopefully you know right
side note i love allison that you have gary the
gecko behind you i absolutely understand back that
up is you want to be your authentic self put what
you love around you so also other side note is i
didn't know his name was gary until you just said
that so thank you now i know his name is barry
ask your recruiter in your next geico interview
because it's impressive when people
know gary's name exactly exactly
great thanks um so somebody asked in the
discussion group um how to make the most of those
potentially up to 10 minutes worth of chat with a
recruiter on brazen time just seems to fly by and
they went to a career fair in the fall semester
so they know how quickly that can go by so maybe
how to best utilize those up to 10 minutes that
you may have with a recruiter i know some folks
mentioned preparing some statements in advance
so if anybody wants to continue into that route
i would really say when you're doing your research
and you're thinking of questions you want to ask
it's easy to sort of frame it as what's going to
make a good impression what question do i think
they'll be impressed by and that's great but i
would stop take a second and actually think about
what is it you want to know or if you have some
concern about this company of why i think this
might not be right do you have something you're
genuinely excited about you want to know more
really think about what it is you want to gain
from the interaction and so that will likely
leave a better impression on the recruiter but
will also make the most of the 10 minutes for
you right and even to go further like uh you know
tiffany as jiminy mentioned doing the research on
the company beforehand not even doing research
on the company beforehand but researching the
positions that you're interested in nobody
is going to have the information like your
recruiter is going to have nobody's going to be
able to give you that insight so when you guys
are interacting with us one-on-one don't be afraid
to say on my resume you know is there any do you
see red flags here you know advice is that we can
see and we can directly control in the moment so
skills that we look for for certain positions um
technologies that are used that are companies that
we frequently look for um and even down to hey
look at my resume make sure this is in the right
order or formatted correctly those are things
that we can help you with so let us help you there
i agree 100 with both ally and allison um
essentially it comes down to pre-event preparation
uh and and yeah optimizing based on what you want
and what you want to get out of the meeting with
with us or any recruiter or staff that you sit
with and that could be exactly just writing
down a couple questions that you want to ask the
resume critiques always great always great to do
um so it's essentially imagine it like an
aspect of virtual networking so i've led a few
uh networking whether virtual or in person uh you
know little little lessons or you know 101 flash
talks if you know if you want to call that and the
and even if you research or google you know how to
network the first and foremost thing they say is
write down what you want to get out of it what are
your goals what do you want to accomplish so if
it's okay you applied to these jobs and you want
to know hey what's the status of your application
prepare you're not you're going to be talking with
you know you know this company and you applied
make sure you write that down you want to ask
about this job you want to talk about their resume
you want to ask them you know whatever questions
that you want to get to your goals that's
probably the best way to keep yourself on track
uh because when you are your authentic
self and you get into a casual conversation
it's very easy to also get sidetracked on the
more fun things and to you know new questions
come about but if you have it right in front of
you if you've prepped and you know what you want
to get out of it you can help yourself and keep
yourself um just to optimize that time i will
also just add that a great thing to close with
is always what would be the next step how should
i email you do i submit an application where do i
submit it knowing that that's a first interaction
of the career fair and it's at the stage where you
are seeking out as many opportunities as possible
so what you're trying to do is get to the next
step of actually applying of furthering that
interaction so always know what happens after
this um and go ahead and just ask that question
that's a great point and actually will lead me to
my next question um a student asked pre submitted
how can i increase my chances of getting an
interview after meeting you at the career fair
following up um it's it's that simple because
it it shows also that you have some kind of
drive that you are somehow interested it's not
just being like oh we met you in person and we
know you now and it's showing that you're somehow
diligent and on top of it and trying to move this
process forward um you've made a connection and
take it somewhere there's a reason the job fair is
called connections um follow up with the recruiter
if that's if you have their contact information
or if you've asked you know what the next step
is just follow up on whatever the next step
they've told you is because that's how the system
works and that's how they take in new applicants
and like even if you've connected with
somebody at a career fair don't be afraid
to go to their careers website and look at the
other opportunities that are available either
because what i have seen happen is i'll send
out a link to somebody and they may apply or
they may not and then they'll follow up with
me about opportunities and it's like well
when's the last time that you visited
our career site and applied to something
and i know that seems a little you're like but i
want to talk to somebody first i understand but
getting your application and your resume there is
going to be step one sometimes um so that is my
that's my biggest encouragement is don't be afraid
to go and seek the opportunities on their website
and in your follow-up say hey allison i went to
geico's website on my own and i applied to 15 jobs
now make sure you're make sure you're tailoring
your resume to each of those and are qualified
but that's great then i have kind of a jumping off
point even so if you want to take it like a step
further too don't be afraid
to look at what's out there
and i'll add um always ask for feedback so when
you're out at a job fair when you're out at a
networking event uh you know whatever wherever
you're at and you're talking with recruiters
um you know of course as we know recruiters
are talking to you know hundreds of applicants
recruiters and and hiring managers are looking
at hundreds of resumes right so how do you stand
down the question is okay how how do i stand out
how can i um you know just be seen above the rest
and i'll be quite frank with you i will and
you know not everyone's going to find one right
each each individual job each position at each
level they're going to require specific things
and and recruiters and hiring managers are going
to want to find people that fit and align with xyz
right as the position requires it so how
can you make sure you you fair or how can
you make sure you get an interview ask ask
for feedback much like the the resume review
that allison had mentioned you know bring your
resume hey you know i love this position this
looks like something i want to get to based
on the job description it may not be you know
i may not be there exactly you know be real with
yourself too you know i may not be exactly there
how can i get there i've had students come up
to me at career fairs not necessarily wanting
a job or not you know of course they want a job
but not necessarily you know expecting but they
came up to me and was really humble saying what
else can i put on my resume what's missing on my
resume to make me stand out and again to be that
vulnerable real self and to know that maybe for
that particular position there might not be a
match now but if you keep asking for feedback
getting direction from the recruiters and the and
the hiring managers and hiring teams you will get
there so don't be afraid to ask what's missing and
to ask for feedback on how to continuously improve
great thank you all so much for the insight um
speaking of follow-up after the fair we had a
question asked and i get this question a lot
as a career advisor is should these students
try to connect with you on linkedin and if you
are okay with that how should they go about that
you can absolutely connect with me on linkedin my
name is just tiffany and in order for me to
accept your connection you gotta tell me a joke
no i'm just kidding you can definitely tell me a
joke if you like but just send me a request and
i'll be happy to connect with you um you can
absolutely add us on linkedin we do suggest
because we're a hiring agency there's a there's a
office linkedin that we suggest people people add
to instead of individual's um but yeah absolutely
because it can be a resource for so many people
yeah here at geico all of the recruiters we do
have linkedin accounts for each of the recruiters
for our regions um so that's really exciting that
not only here do we connect you with recruiters um
a recruiter in general but we're
going to connect you with the correct
so it goes it's just a step past that so if
like our management development programs or
even our technology development programs you
might speak to me or you might speak to one
of the chelseas in virginia right so we have
lots of different people who handle things so
i'm always encouraging candidates and applicants
to reach out to their respective recruiters um
even a little more general right like when
you're going on linkedin to connect with
employers and recruiters um go in again with the
same mindset of here is something that i want out
of this conversation and here's how i'm going
to attempt to get it even if it's hey allison
saw you on linkedin um solve this position on
geico's careers website i'm going to apply her
i have applied right so i get a lot i have get
no i've gotten a lot of emails that are like
hey i'm going to apply that doesn't do much for
me as a recruiter the ones that if you'd be like
hey i have applied to this position can you let me
know because then i again that jumping off point i
can go in and say okay this person applied there
on this next step or hey this person applied and
they got rejected from the process why did they
get stuck like what is the reason and how can i
help um and that's kind of uh that's my take on
linkedin and of course you can connect with me
thanks so we have another good question in the
chat of what we've mentioned so far about some
of the questions i know tiffany said the top five
questions that she gets every single career fair
um kind of the cookie cutter version and instead
try to ask some more memorable questions that
show you've done your research show you're
really passionate and care about this position
um so catherine had asked what are some
questions that you have been asked recently
that were really memorable or
really made you sit back and think
can you think of any off the top of your head
you might want to share with with the audience
i think um some of the questions that
were really great for me and you know
the five ten minutes uh conversations
we're really about how that individual
can learn and pursue their you know their
passions their academic or professional interests
and what opportunities do they have to give back
to the community right and i think that's that
speaks volumes about that the characteristics of
those individuals and and what they want to do
and you know if they're culturally aligned right
to the values of that company um so really you
know questions questions that that kind of show
who you are right and show what you want to do
show your own personal mission um and how you want
to impact impact the world because at mantec we we
solve our government's problems we partner heavily
with uh government agencies across the world
and we develop system solutions to to really make
the world a more secure place and that is mission
oriented that's mission critical right there
uh so to me that spoke out that question spoke
out to me a lot because it really aligns with
our uh company culture uh so along with that
you know as everybody you know even me right i've
been in in the interview process i've applied for
jobs right as we all have one of the best pieces
of advice that i had ever gotten was to of course
look at the company website but to look at the uh
the the values right the values or the principles
or you know just the buzzwords that they have in
the culture and tail your conversation around that
tailor your questions around those aspects of the
company because again that shows your alignment
both culturally from an innovation standpoint from
a personality and behavior standpoint it shows
your alignment to the company and and recruiters
and hiring managers will remember that thank you
anyone else with some of the memorable questions
i would i would say something very similar a
question that shows how your experience relates
to what you think the company is looking
for something that gives a little insight
to your perspective um is going to be something
that is going to get you the information that
you want better as well as helping the recruiter
remember you because they have actually learned
something about you so a lot what you said about
showing yourself and your personality yeah yeah
100 i think there are definitely different
questions for different scenarios too so
just being aware of like where you are
um you know usually if you're in the
uh career fair space right like if you're in
this one on one space where you're getting this
feedback you probably want to ask questions
related to um some more of the general more
of the overview topics and then if you're doing
a recruiter phone screen where you've already
sent me your transcripts you sent me your resume
make sure that you're tailoring the question to
that particular position um so some of my
favorite questions from you know some technology
development uh program applicants that i've had
are you know what technologies are your companies
using what is the structure in your technology
organization um you know asking uh questions about
um methodologies or concepts that we look at using
right like things that students as students you
can work on things that do not change across
industry but you can get specific information
um so so do think about you know
questions that can help you keep growing
great thank you and we have five minutes left
and i know i need to stay on time um so i have
two more pre-submitted questions that i'm going to
try to get through for the folks asking questions
in the discussion group i'm so glad you're asking
questions and engaging please stay for the last 45
minutes where you can talk to all these recruiters
one-on-one in the chat booths as well as current
professional development advisors where you
can continue to ask your individual questions
so uh one of the questions that was pre-submitted
that i want to touch on is the elevator pitch
what are the elements that are really important
really make an elevator pitch stand out for you
i love the elevator pitch i gotta tell you um
i first learned what an elevator pitch when i
was in sales because i and i don't know if you
all know this but an elevator pitch is named so
because literally sales people would have only 30
seconds and if you're in the elevator for instance
with a key person that's it you have 30 seconds or
less to give that pitch and to make that lasting
impression um i'll give you a real real little
example too uh in prior to spam tech i worked at
another company uh same thing running the student
programs uh in college recruiting program and i
actually got into the elevator with one of the uh
vps and i was new at the time and i literally i
had my elevator pitch ready to go and i whipped
it out uh in the elevator that sounds bad sorry
please excuse that but i basically stated my
elevator pitch to that person and that person
well we we had a great relationship you know
we we talked a lot about recruiting we talked
about stats we talked about how to improve the
pipeline so it works so to answer your question
the three aspects that i always recommend
people when developing their elevator pitch
is one who you are you know what's your name
uh two what your what your title is or position
or you know in this case if you're a student
where do you go to school what are you majoring in
and three what is the impact that you have right
so what does the impact that your work does
so if you're if you have a job right and
you're saying okay well this you know i
impact this project and this helps blah blah blah
or if you're in school and you're uh you know
let's just say type security major uh you know
you state your name your your school your major
and what classes or even academic projects you've
done that highlight your passion for cyber and how
they've impacted you know x y and z so those
are my three uh three aspects of the pitch
so for me an elevator pitch when you're looking
at it when you're in a career fair um the career
fair setting i am looking for um eligibility
requirements right so when you come to me you
say you know my name is allison hanson i am a
junior with an anticipated graduation date of x
i am studying why my gpa is abc and i'm really
excited to learn more about this position
or looking in looking to get into this field um i
know that your company has this department um can
you tell me a little bit more about that right
so even right there that is that is somewhat of
an elevator right i've told you who i am what i'm
interested in what about your company interests me
and i've given you a call to action so i've
asked you as somebody else to give me information
i didn't already have specifically a department
right so if you're a cyber security major ask how
big is your cyber security you know and and that
question lets them know that you're interested in
the area as well so just to build off of that um
really when someone gives you an elevator pitch
the thing that kind of to me always
marks it as okay this is great or
this is completely irrelevant to what i'm doing
is the person giving the pitches self-awareness
do they understand their position how it relates
to mine and how our goals are somehow in line so
it is kind of what you were saying with values
but it requires a little bit of self-evaluation
an elevator pitch is all about really knowing
yourself well enough to present yourself
so looking at your background your goals and how
where you are in between those things and how you
present your background to help you move towards
your goals is what you want to look at so your
elevator pitch won't be the same necessarily to
every recruiter you talk to you're gonna have
the same foundation but you do want to change up
a little something so that it makes sense with
the goals of whoever you're talking to i think
you back off of that just a little bit you know it
because of ali it really boils down to confidence
right so i encourage my students just like tiffany
said you know your passion projects the reason
why we say these things we want you to give us
your most confident foot forward speak about the
things that you know you know i mean that's what
that's what's going to set you apart from your
peers is really knowing how to talk about yourself
right so thank you thank you so
much to all three of our panelists
for sharing such great information and for taking
the time to join us for the first half of today's
event so quick little run of applause virtual
round of applause uh please remember that you
can visit career and professional development's
website at career.vt.edu for more information and
resources on preparing for a virtual career fair
and so much more um and please feel free to make
an appointment with us at vt.joinhandshake.com
we will be moving into our one-on-one networking
portion of the event where you will be able to
get in line to speak with a company representative
one of these four today um or meet with a
career advisor for the career professional
development booth please remember that at the
networking boost we'll close promptly at 5 pm
and you will receive a brief survey
a few minutes after the event today
to gather some feedback on today's program thank
you so much again for attending digital connect
and good luck to everybody at their
career fairs thank you thank you all